DEREK HUBBARD

SOFTWARE CRAFTSMAN

PROFILE

I am a creative and inquisitive software engineer with over 15 years of experience developing exceptional user interfaces and first-class products. I have a passion for front-end experiences but also enjoy the challenge of building large, scalable server-side solutions. I approach new problems with a pragmatic point of view, and am both an early adopter and a fast adapter. I like helping organizations identify new opportunities and challenges; leading and mentoring agile teams as they work toward meeting those challenges is exciting.

CONTACT

✓ derek@derekhubbard.com

937,572,9214

derekhubbard.com

derekhubbard

EXPERIENCE

POMIET 2013 - PRESENT

SOFTWARE CRAFTSMAN

Leveraged new and emerging technologies to create exceptional user experiences and the best products possible for clients in the healthcare sector. Helped clients identify opportunities and business needs, and then worked with them to break larger development efforts down into smaller, managable deliverables. Led geographically-distributed and cross-functional agile teams, guiding them to deliver custom applications for both web and mobile devices. Researched and evaluated technical solutions by first developing a solid understanding of the problem domain, and then architecting simple solutions to model that domain. Effectively articulated advanced technical topics to both technical development teams and non-technical clients. Leveraged automation and continuous feedback throughout the entire application development process, including builds, deployments, testing and infrastructure. Mentored team members, coaching them through achieving their own personal and company growth goals.

APPLIED INFORMATION SCIENCES 2011 - 2013

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Developed scalable, RESTful, enterprise web services for clients in the automotive insurance sector using the latest technologies in the industry. Led large, geographically-distributed agile teams, guiding them to research, evaluate, and prototype scalable solutions using a variety of enterprise software patterns, including messaging and asychronous communication. Led the development and configuration of infrastructure to support the build, deployment and testing of our solutions.

STRATEGIC DATA SYSTEMS 2009 - 2011

SENIOR CONSULTANT & MICROSOFT ALM TECHNICAL SPECIALIST

Led the development and delivery of multiple custom business solutions that utilize proven patterns while providing guidance and training on Application Lifecycle Management (ALM) processes and software development best practices. Developed a rich internet application with supporting web services for a healthcare case management company. Provided guidance, mentoring, and customization support on Microsoft Application Lifecycle Management (ALM) tools and Scrum with Microsoft Team Foundation Server. Developed a mobile video streaming application that targeted iOS and Windows Phone 7 mobile platforms. Independently developed a custom Google Maps implementation for a realty company, integrating Google StreetView images and Google Local Search.

EXPERIENCE

THE BERRY COMPANY 2007 - 2009

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Designed, developed, and implemented web and windows applications in support of company-wide marketing, sales, and product fulfillment initiatives. Lead developer for requirements gathering, design, and development of scalable customer portal CMS website, which allowed external customers and internal employees to view product offerings and statistics. Collaborated with developers at Google to enhance, test, and deploy a custom application to manage customers' Google AdWords accounts. Designed and developed a vendor feed maintenance application to aggregate product statistics from vendors in a centralized database through the use of web services, which allowed for the reporting of product statistics and customer leads on a daily basis within a customer portal website.

SOFTWARE ARCHITECTS 2004 - 2007

SENIOR CONSULTANT

Designed, developed, and delivered scalable custom business applications and solutions for clients in the Cincinnati/Northern Kentucky area. Designed high availability infrastructure for critical aircraft engine messaging system. Gained experience in an array of industries with well-known clients in the financial services and aviation industries.

KODAK VERSAMARK 2002 - 2004

BUSINESS SYSTEMS ANALYST

Developed and implemented application software in support of the company's graphic and printing products. Designed and developed application code using custom scripts, functions, stored procedures, packages, triggers for Oracle applications.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

ELIXIR, PHOENIX HTML, CSS, SASS, LESS **POSTGRESQL** NODE.JS, JAVASCRIPT, EXPRESS INFERNO, REACT, REDUX **MONGODB** RUBY, RAILS **METEOR MYSQL** .NET, C#, ASP.NET **WEBPACK SQL SERVER** PHP, WORDPRESS JASMINE, MOCHA, JEST **ORACLE** JAVA **CUCUMBER** ADOBE INDESIGN **BASH** WINDOWS, UNUX ADOBE PREMIER GIT, TFS, SUBVERSION **CHEF** ADOBE PRELUDE

VIRTUALIZATION

FXPFRTISE

AGILE, SCRUM
TEST DRIVEN DEVELOPMENT
DOMAIN DRIVEN DESIGN
RESPONSIVE WEB DESIGN
ACCEPTANCE TESTING
CONTINUOUS INTEGRATION
INFRASTRUCTURE AUTOMATION

SPECIALTIES



Domain Driven Design



Architecture



Test Driven Development

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, COMPUTER ENGINEERING

MATHEMATICS MINOR

University of Dayton 1999 - 2004

HOBBIES & INTERESTS











